Guide to the Wells Fargo Steinbeck Collection, 1892-1981
Department of Special Collections
- Series 12. John Steinbeck Books and Articles
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. [Malory, Thomas, Sir, 15th cent.]. The acts of King Arthur and his noble knights: from the Winchester Manuscripts of Thomas Malory and other sources / John Steinbeck; edited by Chase Horton. New York: Farrar, Straus and Giroux, c1976. xiii, 363 p.; 24 cm., First edition.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Steinbeck: a life in letters / edited by Elaine Steinbeck and Robert Wallsten. New York: The Viking Press, 1975. xv, 906 p.: port.; 25 cm., Inscribed on free endpaper (in Elaine Steinbeck's hand) "For Esther | In Memory of John | Elaine Steinbeck"; (in Robert Wallsten's hand) "Robert Wallsten | Oct 1975"
  - Ricketts, Edward Flanders, 1896-1948. Between Pacific tides; an account of the habits and habitats of some five hundred of the common, conspicuous seashore invertebrates of the Pacific coast between Sitka, Alaska, and northern Mexico / [by] Edward F. Ricketts and Jack Calvin. Foreword by John Steinbeck; line drawings by Ritchie Lovejoy. 3rd edition, revised, revisions by Joel W. Hedgpeth. Stanford, California: Stanford University Press, [1962]. xiii, 516 p. illus. (part col.) maps, diagrs. 24 cm., Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on verso of front free endpaper.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. [Cannery Row. Norwegian] Late menn og muntre piker / John Steinbeck; oversatt av Nils Lie. Oslo: Gyldendals Lommebøker, 1953. 207 p.; 17 cm., Goldstone, D401b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. [Sweet Thursday. French] Tendre jeudi (Sweet Thursday): Rue de la sardine II: roman / John Steinbeck; traduit de l'americain par J.C. Bonnardot. Paris: Éditions Mondiales, c1956. 256 p.; 17 cm. Le livre de poche; 1536., Goldstone, D173b[?].
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. [Short reign of Pippin IV. German] Lasst uns könig spielen: ein fabriziertes Märchen / John Steinbeck; [Deutsch von Harry Kahn]. Stuttgart and Konstanz: Diana Verlag, c1962. 203, [5] p.; 20 cm. Diana Reihe; 66, Goldstone, D214.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. [Sweet Thursday. Dutch] Goede donderdag / John Steinbeck; [vertaling, E. D. Künzli-Boissevain]. Amsterdam: Em. Querido's Uitgeverij N.V., c1969. 190 p.; 19 cm. Salamander; 96.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. [The winter of our discontent. Dutch] Wintertij van tegenzin / door John Steinbeck; geautoriseerde vertaling, Rein F. Herman. Amsterdam: Em. Querido's Uitgeverij N.V., c1968. 253, [2] p.; 19 cm. Salamander; 215. van tegenzin. Amsterdam: Querido.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. [Travels with Charley. Dutch. 1969] Op reis met Charley: op zoek naar Amerika / John Steinbeck; geautoriseerde vertaling, Rein F. Herman. Amsterdam: Em. Querido's Uitgeverij N.V., c1969. 222, [1] p.; 19 cm. Salamander; 234., Signed on front cover: "Esther Rodgers"
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. [The short reign of Pippin IV. Swedish] Konung för en dag / John Steinbeck; [oversattning av Vanja Lantz]. Stockholm: Bokförlaget Aldus/Bonniers, 1971. 141, [9] p.; 19 cm. Delfinserien; 398., Goldstone, D564.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. [The Pastures of Heaven. Dutch] Het beloofde land / John Steinbeck; [vertaling, M. G. Binnendijk-Paauw]. Amsterdam: Em. Querido's Uitgeverij N.V., 1971. 191 p.; 19 cm. Salamander; 168, Goldstone, D128.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. [Cannery Row. Dutch] Een blik in Cannery Row / John Steinbeck; [geautoriseerde vertaling, L. I. Brugmans-Martens]. Amsterdam: Em. Querido's Uitgeverij N.V., c1974. 191 p.; 19 cm. Salamander; 334.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. [The Pearl. Dutch] De parel / John Steinbeck; [vertaling, E. D. Veltman-Boissevain]. Amsterdam: Em. Querido's Uitgeverij N.V., 1971. 156, [4] p.; 19 cm. Salamander; 38.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Conversation at Sag Harbor. Holiday. Vol. 29, no. 3 (March 1961), 60-61, 129-131, 133., Goldstone, C170.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The Winter of Our Discontent [condensed]. McCall's. Vol. 88, no. 8 (May 1961), 69-70, 212-228., Goldstone, C173.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. In quest of America (part one). Holiday. Vol. 30, no. 1 (July 1961), [26], 27-33, 79-85., Goldstone, C174.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. In quest of America (part three). Holiday. Vol. 31, no. 2 (Feb. 1962), 58-63, 122-123., Goldstone, C177.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. A Snake of One's Own. The Best: A Continuing Anthology of the world's greatest writing. Vol. 1, no. 2 (Winter 1965), 292-300., Text from The Long Valley. Goldstone, C189.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. America and the Americans. The Saturday Evening Post. 239th year, issue no. 14 (July 2, 1966), [32] 33-38, 40-41, 44, 46-47., Goldstone, C192.
  - Nolan, William F. Wrapped and Shellacked. Carte Blanche. Vol. 1, No. 7 (Summer 1966).
  - Gannett, Lewis Stiles, 1891-. John Steinbeck: personal and bibliographical notes / by Lewis Gannett. New York: The Viking Press, 1939. 14 p. front. (port.) 21 cm.
  - Moore, Harry Thornton. The novels of John Steinbeck: a first critical study / by Harry Thornton Moore. Chicago: Normandie House, 1939. 102 p., 1 incl. front. (map) 22 cm., Signed by Esther Rodgers on front free endpaper.
  - Fontenrose, Joseph Eddy, 1903-. John Steinbeck: an introduction and interpretation / Joseph Fontenrose. New York: Barnes & Noble, 1963. ix, 150 p.: ill., ports.; 22 cm.
  - Johnston, Robert B. (Robert Burney), 1906-. St. Paul's Episcopal Church, 1873-1973: a centennial history / by Robert B. Johnston. [Salinas, Calif.: St. Paul's Episcopal Church, [1973]. 95 p. ill., ports.; 23 cm., "Printed by Pajaro Press, Watsonville, Calif." Signed by Esther Rodgers on front cover. Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on verso of front free endpaper. Includes the account of an incident in which 11- or 12-year-old John Steinbeck, carrier of the choir cross, watched in "horror" as the cross he had failed to fasten securely came loose, crashing "on the glistening pate of the Bishop and [felling] him." Steinbeck subsequently lost the coveted position of crossbearer to his friend, "Skunkfoot."
  - Valjean, Nelson, 1901-. John Steinbeck, the errant knight: an intimate biography of his California years / by Nelson Valjean. San Francisco: Chronicle Books, c1975. 184, [7] p.: ill.; 24 cm., Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on front paste-down. Inscribed "Esther Rodgers" on front free endpaper.
  - Lisca, Peter. John Steinbeck, nature and myth / Peter Lisca. New York: Thomas Y. Crowell Company, c1978. viii, 245, [1] p.; 21 cm. Twentieth-century American writers., Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on front paste-down.
  - Schmitz, Anne-Marie. In search of Steinbeck / Anne-Marie Schmitz; photography by Richard S. Mayer; illustrations by Wayne Garcia. Los Altos, Calif.: Hermes Publications, 1978. xiv, 31 p.: ill.; 25 cm., Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on front paste-down. From Colophon: "Typesetting in Linotype Granjon by Theodore Lidga and hand-set Carolus types by Alan Ligda. Color separations by Preston Kimball. Printed on Curtis India Tweedweave Paper by Del Rey Printing Company; Stewart Clark, Pressman. Bound in Record Natural Buckram cloth from Holliston Mills by Roswell Bookbinding. Bindery production arranged by Joel S. Shefflin and Dana Monosoff of Peter G. Levison Associates. Designed by Alan Ligda. One thousand two hundred copies printed, of which this is copy number 5" Inscribed on colophon: "To Esther, John Steinbeck's sister | Anne-Marie Schmitz" In slip case.
  - John Steinbeck: a guide to the collection of the Salinas Public Library / edited by John Gross and Lee Richard Hayman. Salinas, Calif.: Salinas Public Library, 1979. 196 p.: ill., ports.; 22 cm., Inscribed on half-title page: "To Mrs. Rodgers | With warm regards | John Gross / 2/7/80" Half-title label: "Cover portrait | Gift of the artist | WAYNE GARCIA" "This is NUMBER 31 of the limited edition of two hundred numbered copies published in February 1979." Signed on half-title page by the editors.
  - Kiernan, Thomas. The intricate music: a biography of John Steinbeck / Thomas Kiernan. 1st ed. Boston: Little, Brown, c1979. xvii, 331 p.: port; 24 cm., Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on front paste-down.
  - Andersen, H. C. (Hans Christian), 1805-1875. Andersen's Fairy Tales: Illustrated. Springfield, MA: McLoughlin Brothers, n.d. [1900?] 185 p.: ill.; 26 cm., Inscription in pencil on verso of front free endpaper: "Carolee | from | John | & | Carol."
  - Steinbeck, John, IV, 1946-. In touch / [by] John Steinbeck, IV. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1969. xiv, 202 p. 22 cm., "Publication date, February 26, 1969" "First and second Printings before publication" Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on front paste-down.